

Matthew Rose

Senior Software Engineer at Scout

matt@scoutapp.com

Summary

Over ten years experience developing web applications, mostly in Ruby on Rails, Javascript (Backbone/Angular/Ember), and some Go. Future development interests include more Ruby, while excited about possibilities with Elixir/ Phoenix and Go (Clojure? Scala?), which I have been exploring through toy projects. Work experience including server/application monitoring applications, e-commerce, inventory and project information management. Advanced degree in Management Information Systems.

Community involvement includes starting and running Fort Collins Ruby Group for five years. Strength in communicating technical information to non-technical users. Coding style: collaborative, clean, behavior-driven, with test coverage.

Experience

Software Engineer at Scout Monitoring

May 2013 - Present (2 years 9 months)

A small team (total company size has grown from 3 to 6 people during my employment) building and maintaining a high-throughput web service for monitoring server and application health. Clients include Apple, Adobe, Sendgrid, AirBnB, NPR, etc. scoutapp.com

Software Engineer/Owner at Composition9, LLC

2005 - May 2013 (8 years)

Freelance software development, mostly web, mostly Ruby on Rails. Projects I contracted on include http://push.io (bought by Oracle), https://www.thislife.com (bought by Shutterfly), http://www.bulley.com/ (inventory management system), http://www.resourcerevival.com/, PocketFuzz: http://techcrunch.com/2007/09/16/pocketfuzz-announces-service-to-make-concerts-more-annoying/, etc.

Systems Developer/Accountant at Bulley & Andrews, LLC

January 2000 - January 2005 (5 years 1 month)

Worked as accountant while attaining Masters degree. Later, built a project/inventory management system that I still maintain (see above).

Education

DePaul University - Charles H. Kellstadt Graduate School of Business

Master of Science, Management Information Systems 2004, 2000 - 2004

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Bachelor of Arts, Economics; Accounting & Accountancy Economic Statistics, 1995 - 2000

Interests

spending time with my kids, new technology, camping, hiking, skiing, bicycling

Skills & Expertise

- Ruby
 Ruby on Rails
 JavaScript
 AngularJS
 Ember.js
 PostgreSQL
 Go
 Elixir
 MySQL
 CSS
 Git

- Git
- RESTAgile Methodologies